SOFIE WALLIN





Location: Linköping, Sweden

Born: 8 may 1984

Phone: +46 73-027 98 16

Email: sofie.wallin84@gmail.com

Web: sofiewallin.github.io
LinkedIn: /sofie-wallin

GitHub: /sofiewallin

Design

- UX/UI design
- Responsive web design
- Graphic design and branding

Web development

- HTML5 and
- CSS3/Sass
- JavaScript and React
- TypeScript
- WordPress (PHP)
- Accessibility (WCAG)
- Git and GitHub

Language skills

- Swedish (native)
- English (fluent)

Who am I?

I design and code websites and applications with the user in mind. I have worked with this professionally for over a decade, sometimes as a pure UX/UI designer, but during most of these years also as a web developer, mainly on the client side. I am very comfortable in the user interface and passionate about creating digital solutions that are intuitive, usable and accessible.

Work experience

Design lead and front-end developer at 84codes

Aug 2020-Feb 2023 / Stockholm (remote)

84codes offers hosting and fully managed servers for message queues, mainly RabbitMQ. During my time there I mostly worked with UX, analysis, UI design and frontend development.

UX/UI design • Haml (Ruby) • Jekyll • HTML5 • CSS3/Sass • Bootstrap • JavaScript and React • Git and GitHub

Web developer and graphic designer at Storbildsfabriken

Jan 2013-Jan 2018 / Linköping

Storbildsfabriken works with printed and digital communication. My role was mainly to design and develop several websites and interfaces for them, but I also worked with graphic design and marketing.

UX/UI design • Graphic design and branding • HTML5 • CSS3 • WordPress (PHP) • JavaScript • SEO • Digital marketing

Web designer at Noc Webbyrå

Feb 2011-Sep 2012 / Linköping

Noc Webbyrå delivered websites and digital solutions. My role was mainly as a UI designer, where I worked closely with the customers and had a strategic responsibility. I also helped with web development.

UX/UI design · HTML · CSS · WordPress (PHP) · Git



Characteristics

- Analytical
- Open-minded
- Creative
- Quality conscious
- Responsible
- Planning

Interests

- Sustainability
- Nature experiences
- Minimalism
- Running and yoga
- Singing and music
- Video games and series

Web designer at Langustus Industrier

July 2009-Feb 2011 / Norrköping

Langustus Industrier was a web agency that mainly delivered websites. As a web designer, I worked closely with customers and assisted with UX/UI design, graphic design and web development, mostly frontend.

UX/UI design • Graphic design and branding • HTML • CSS • JavaScript

Freelance web designer

Nov 2008–Dec 2011 / Norrköping and Linköping

Alongside my studies and employment, I was hired for a period by several companies and smaller organizations to deliver websites.

UI design • Graphic design and branding • HTML • CSS • WordPress (PHP)

Education

Web development at the Mid Sweden University

Aug 2020-June 2022 / Sundsvall (remote) / 120 hp

I have 97.5 HE credits from the web development program at the Mid Sweden University, which has given me a broad knowledge in web development, from UX to backend.

HTML5 · CSS3/Sass · JavaScript and React · Node.js · TypeScript · SQL · NoSQL · Headless CMS · REST-APIs · PHP · WordPress · C# and .NET · Accessibility (WCAG) · Git and GitHub

Graphic design and communication at Linköping University

Aug 2006-June 2009 / Norrköping / 180 hp

I have a bachelor's degree in graphic design and communication from Linköping University, which gave me a broad knowledge of the field.

Graphic profiling and brands • Typography • Layout • Digital image production • Interaction design • Information design • Marketing and communication